[ TENSE MUSIC PLAYS ]
WARD : West of Arkham
the hills rise wild
and there are valleys with deep woods
that no ax has ever cut .
There are dark , narrow glens
where the trees slope fantastically
where thin brooklets trickle
without ever having caught the glimpse of sunlight .
When I went into the hills and vales
to survey for the new reservoir ,
they told me the place was evil .
They told me this in Arkham ,
and because that is a very old town ,
full of witch legends ,
I thought the evil must be something
which grandams had whispered to children
through centuries .
Then I saw the dark westward tangle of glens
and slopes for myself
and ceased to wonder at anything
besides its own elder mystery .
[ DOWN-TEMPO MUSIC PLAYING ]
Before me , Raphael .
Behind me , Gabriel .
To my left
Uriel .
And to my right , Michael .
I call upon the principalities of earth ,
air , fire , water , and ether .
Be present with me now .
Spirit of fire ,
continue to burn out
any trace of cancer
from the body of Theresa Gardner , my mother .
Grant me your protection .
Grant me my freedom .
And last , not least ,
get me out of here .
- [ RUSTLING ] - [ HORSE WHINNIES ]
I 'm sorry . I 'm sorry to intrude .
- I didn 't see you . - This is private property .
Oh , I was told this is county land .
County land ends at the river . You 're trespassing .
Ah . They said the mayor notified all the property owners .
- Uh , I apologize . - First I 've heard of it .
What now ?
Sorry . I 'm , uh ... I 'm Ward Phillips .
I 'm doing a survey of the valley for Hydrolit .
The hydroelectric company .
Cool story .
Well , thanks for ruining my ritual , Ward .
- WARD : Ritual ? - Yes , ritual .
You know , will , intent , blessed be ?
Is it Wiccan or Alexandrian ?
Which do you think ?
Definitely Alexandrian .
That 's your second mistake today .
Stick to the east bank and you 'll find your way back .
Yeah , I will . Thanks .
Hey , uh , I didn 't get your name .
Lavinia Gardner .
I live out here . Unfortunately .
- Let 's go . - Nice knowing you .
Come on , Comet .
[ DOWN-TEMPO MUSIC PLAYS ]
[ HORSE WHINNIES ]
Where were you ?
Are you trying to give your mother a heart attack ?
I just thought I 'd take Comet around the trail before dinner .
It 's not a big deal .
And I thought I told you not to go without your helmet .
And where are your boots ? What happened to your boots ?
Dad , Jesus , relax . It 's not like I 'm trick riding .
Accidents happen , Lavinny . Someday ...
I 'll have kids of my own , and I 'll understand .
Exactly right . See ? Communication . Me and you , babe .
Now get Comet back into the barn before your mother finds out .
Lavinia .
Have you seen your brother ? He 's been gone all afternoon .
He 's supposed to be studying , as are you .
How should I know ?
He 's probably listening to NASA recordings with Ezra .
[ INHALES SHARPLY ]
Do you mean to tell me that your brother is smoking dope
with that hippie reprobate , and you didn 't do anything ?
Lavinia ? You didn 't do anything ?
- Let it go , sweetie . - No .
It 's fine . She 's fine . Everything is fine .
[ SIGHS ]
Benny , I can smell your stoned ass from here .
- Busted . - You 're so obvious .
Sam !
Benny 's little partner in crime .
Hey , I found some more of Grandpa 's old stuff .
- Oh , no way ! - Check this out .
Let me see .
Ooh ! Heh . Dibs .
- No fair ! - You already got his compass .
I need that compass .
Oh . Did you manage to curse us all ?
I don 't do curses .
They come back on you times three .
Now go put Comet 's tack away so we 're on time for dinner ,
and Mom doesn 't bust any more blood vessels .
- I 'm not your barn bitch . - Actually , you are .
Witch . Sorceress . Soul-sucking succubus .
Hey , I met some weird guy down by the river .
Said he was doing a survey .
A survey of what ?
The water table or something .
Not sure .
He 's kind of cute , though .
Aw .
What are you looking at , Jack-Jack ?
JACK : Dad said if you look long enough ,
you can see stars down there .
LAVINIA : Hmm ! I wouldn 't hold my breath .
Dad took too much acid back in the hippie days .
JACK : But I do see stars !
LAVINIA : Your eyes are playing tricks .
W-What are you doing out here , anyway ?
JACK : Dad sent me for water , but I can 't untie the rope .
LAVINIA : Jesus .
Why can 't they just buy bottled water like everyone else ?
Thanks for cooking again , Dad .
Aw , you know I love cooking for you guys .
LAVINIA : Oh , by the smell
I can tell it 's really coming a long way .
- JACK : I miss Mom 's pancakes . - Okay .
So , uh , what is for dinner ?
NATHAN : Cassoulet .
Oh , no . Gross .
NATHAN : It 's a traditional French dish .
In other words , peasant food .
NATHAN : Jack , can you take the lid off the veggies , please ?
- Yeah . - BENNY : I think it smells great .
LAVINIA : That 's because you 're high .
Shut up . We all know you 'd rather be eating
fast food right now , anyway .
I love mystery meat .
Well , this is not mystery meat , dear .
It 's a mélange of duck , pork , regional spices ,
and it just happens to be your mother 's favorite .
Yeah ! I love ducks !
Everybody loves ducks .
We are down four pips , but we didn 't get oversold .
The market came up .
No , we don 't want to be selling just yet .
Uh , when I took the short position ,
I was assuming that we 'd get two-to-one on it .
NATHAN : Theresa ! Dinner 's ready !
Look , we have a nice ratio confluence .
NATHAN : It 's getting cold !
Just take a look at the ratio strategy I sent ,
and I 'll call you in an hour ?
Great .
[ TAPS KEY ]
[ GROANS ]
I 'm coming .
NATHAN : You 're not gonna have it ? Really ?
Babe , can you do something about that router ?
I 'm gonna start losing clients .
It 's probably the dish . I 'll take a look at it tomorrow .
Oh , thank you .
- [ DOG WHINING ] - Hmm .
Sam , lie down .
Good boy .
- What 's this ? - Cassoulet .
Although apparently our daughter would rather have fast food .
Uh , and just what kind of meat
do you think you 're eating at the Golden Arches ?
I know it 's mechanically retrieved ,
but it tastes like heaven .
Then just wait until you try the alpaca meat next year .
Then you 'll know what heaven is .
No , I 'm gonna puke . No one eats alpacas .
They use them to make sweaters .
I don 't know why you bought them in the first place .
Because they 're the animal of the future , remember ?
Those Mayans knew what they were about .
- That 's why they went extinct . - THERESA : Lavinia , stop it .
Come on , eat up .
Nathan , do you think that you could
go down to the basement and choose us one of your finest ?
I know just the thing .
Next time I 'll cook .
- It 's not that bad . - Yeah .
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATION ]
NATHAN : There 's a smell of a conspiracy here .
[ SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ]
What 's the matter ? Hmm ?
Nothing . It 's just ...
I just don 't think I can handle this .
- Like , it 's been ... - She 's being moody .
... a year of really ...
Guess what time it is ?
- LAVINIA : I mean ... - JACK : No . Don 't say it . Please .
Guess what time it is .
- Dad . - Time for you to do the dishes !
- You ! You ! You ! - No ! Jack ! Jack !
- No , it 's you , Jack . - No !
BENNY : It 's you , Jack . You got to do it .
JACK : Now it 's Lavinia !
LAVINIA : No , it 's not my turn . That 's not how this works .
We have a system in this house . It 's Jack 's turn .
- [ INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS ] - [ OWL HOOTING ]
[ SILVERWARE CLINKING ]
- THERESA : Hey . - Hi .
THERESA : God , you know , I hear myself with her .
I am turning into my mother .
Oh , God .
You couldn 't be any more different than your mother .
Believe me .
That 's what everyone says until they are .
What about me ?
Living on my father 's old farm ,
exactly like I said I never would .
But it 's the first thing you 've ever done
he would have approved of .
[ CHUCKLES ]
Yeah , I can still hear his intellectually abusive voice
in my head .
" You 're never gonna be a painter , Nathan .
So you can just get the fuck out of my sight , Nathan . "
Stop it . It 'll fade .
- Just look at this place , hmm ? - Yeah .
I mean , he wouldn 't even recognize it .
NATHAN : It 's ours .
[ SIGHS ]
Nathan , I ...
Just ...
It 's been six months . Don 't you think we should try ?
I ...
I just ...
I don 't know how you can still be interested in me .
You know I 've always been a leg man .
[ LAUGHS ]
So if I have my legs cut off , would you still love me then ?
Bit kinky , but ...
- [ LAUGHS ] - Yes !
Could tuck you into my carry-on luggage
and enjoy you wherever I go .
Ooh ! Now , that is sexy .
NATHAN : Mmm .
And look at this .
Look at us .
All those years in the big city , and we finally got out .
Yeah .
We 're living the dream .
Maybe it is a dream .
Well , a dream you dream alone is just a dream .
A dream you dream together is reality .
[ INSECTS CHIRPING , BIRD CALLING ]
[ WOOD CREAKING ]
[ UP-TEMPO MUSIC PLAYING ]
You are even more beautiful to me now than ever .
It 's because you took your glasses off .
It 's true .
[ SIGHS ]
I feel , um
tarnished .
Honey
you will always be my golden lady .
- Really ? - Yeah .
I love you .
[ LAUGHS ]
[ WOOD CREAKING ]
[ UP-TEMPO MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ DOG WHINING SOFTLY ]
Oh , hey , Sam . Good boy .
Good boy , Sam .
Oh , you 're not interested in the black hole , Sam ?
Hmm ?
[ CREAKING CONTINUES ]
[ BREATHING SHALLOWLY ]
JACK : Mommy ?
NATHAN : Oh , baby .
THERESA : Oh , my God . I 've missed you .
[ CREAKING CONTINUES ]
[ DOG WHINES ]
Sam ?
Mommy ?
[ BARKING ]
[ ALPACAS BLEATING SOFTLY ]
[ TENSE MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ MUSIC INTENSIFIES ]
- [ BOOM ] - NATHAN : What ? !
- JACK : [ SCREAMING ] - What the hell is that ? !
- Jack ? - Jack ?
NATHAN : Jack ?
Jack . Look at Daddy .
Jack . Jack .
Come here . Come here . Come on up . Come on .
- Look at Daddy . - LAVINIA : Mom ?
Look at Daddy . What are you looking there ?
- BENNY : Dad ? - THERESA : I know .
LAVINIA : What the fuck was that ? An earthquake ?
Just watch your language . Can you watch your language ?
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATION ]
NATHAN : God , what is that smell ?
LAVINIA : Holy fucking shit !
Benny , bring your phone . Come on ! Come on !
BENNY : Smoking like crazy .
NATHAN : No , don 't go near it . Don 't go near it .
Sam , get back inside . Get back inside .
- I said go inside . - LAVINIA : What the hell is that ?
Just go inside !
Jesus . What a mess .
- [ DOG BARKING ] - It smells .
THERESA : Nate !
There 's something wrong with Jack !
Ohh . It 's okay , baby .
You just had a bad dream .
No , I think ... I think he 's in shock .
We should take him to the hospital .
No , it 's over an hour away . Jack , can you talk to Daddy ?
Why does it matter how far away it is ?
- Look at him ! - What the hell happened ?
BENNY : Did you guys hear it ?
It sounded like a propeller plane having an aneurysm .
NATHAN : No , it wasn 't a plane .
[ ICE CUBES CLINKING ]
NATHAN : That smell .
- I don 't know , like , funny . - [ CORK SQUEAKS ]
- [ LIQUID POURING ] - You can still ...
Still smell it now .
I thought it was a nuclear strike .
The Russians and Chinese , dude .
- End-of-the-world shit . - LAVINIA : You wish .
BENNY : We 'd be vaporized , become part of the reaction ,
and convert into pure energy .
LAVINIA : Maybe the meteorite sent an alien plague
infecting the entire fucking planet .
BENNY : Seriously apocalyptic .
- Mommy ? - Yes , baby , I 'm right here !
- My head hurts . - Okay , honey .
Look , um , let 's get you upstairs .
I 'll put you to bed , and you 'll be okay .
- I don 't want to ! - NATHAN : Mm !
No , it 's okay , baby . There 's nothing to be afraid of .
Oh , your son is sick , and this is what you 're gonna do , huh ?
Well , under the circumstances , I don 't see what else I ...
THERESA : Come on . Let 's get you up .
You can sleep with me tonight .
In the morning everything is gonna be okay .
[ SIREN CHIRPS ]
NATHAN : [ GROANS ]
[ INDISTINCT TALKING ]
NATHAN : Mayor Tooma .
Sheriff Pierce . Thank you for coming .
TOOMA : This better be worth my time .
I am so sorry about the smell .
Can you smell it ?
PIERCE : I don 't smell anything .
NATHAN : Like somebody lit a dog on fire .
Well , anyway , that was my front yard .
BENNY : Careful . It 's still hot .
PIERCE : All right . Thanks .
[ CLINKING ]
Something metallic down here .
What the hell happened here ?
[ EXHALES SHARPLY ] Well , it was last night .
I was in bed with my wife .
It was the first time that we , you know , since the operation ,
and then there was this boom ,
like ... like a ... like a sonic boom ,
and a big flash , like a pink light .
Or , actually , I don 't even know what color it was .
It wasn 't like any color I 'd ever seen before ,
and then everything just blew up or fell from the sky .
[ COUGHS ]
What are you doing here ?
Think this is the result of your little ritual yesterday ?
Ha ! If only .
Are you looking at my legs ?
What ? Oh . No . Um ... No , I was ...
Yeah , sure you weren 't . Come on .
[ COUGHING ]
Who 's this ?
Oh , this is that weird guy I met by the river .
Sorry , what was your name again ?
WARD : Ward Phillips .
Let me guess . Boston .
Providence , actually .
He 's doing a survey of the groundwater .
Um , isn 't ... isn 't that what you said yesterday ?
Yeah , yeah . I 'm a ... I 'm a hydrologist .
Ward , do you have any idea what 's going on here ?
Oh , excuse me .
- PIERCE : Hey , Ward . - WARD : Hey .
- Hey . - BENNY : Hey , I 'm Benny .
D-Don 't get too close .
WARD : Uh , looks like a meteorite .
Usually they disintegrate before they hit the ground ,
but not always .
NATHAN : A meteorite ? Whoa .
TOOMA : Sheriff , we need to get some photographs .
Nathan , would you mind if I bring some press next time ?
This can be great for tourism .
I 'd just as soon not publicize it .
Mayor , wait .
Is there a doctor around here who 's open on weekends ?
My son isn 't feeling well ...
You can try the hospital in Arkham .
They usually have somebody on the emergency desk .
- Isn 't there anywhere closer ? - Welcome to life in the sticks .
You know , you should have sold this place to me
while you had the chance .
Bye-bye .
- Isn 't it insane ? - [ CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS ]
Check it out .
TOOMA : Hurry !
Lavinia , can you go back inside and check on your mother ?
Dad !
It 's okay . We got this covered .
Off you go .
[ CLEARS THROAT ]
- LAVINIA : See you later . - Yeah .
Why don 't you go check on her ?
- Be careful . - Okay .
It 's cooling off really fast now .
Is that normal ?
[ INDISTINCT CONVERSATION ]
Smoke coming out of it , crazy color .
- It was so cool . - Okay .
You ever seen anything like this before ?
WARD : Um ...
Hey . Who 's that guy ?
Who ?
Um , Ward something .
- He 's a hydrologist . - Oh .
- You like him , huh ? - What ? No .
Why would you say that ?
Oh , well , come on . It was obvious .
You were practically throwing yourself at him .
- I mean , honey ... - Mom .
Think ... Look at the way you 're dressed .
Think of the signals you 're giving out .
Oh , God .
Do you think it 's radioactive like kryptonite ?
Christ , I hope not .
Well , what about , like , an alien virus ?
I mean , it 's from space , right ?
Meteorites are generally no more dangerous
than ordinary rocks .
Well , do you think it could be valuable ?
Now , that 's something I hadn 't considered .
Well , if you don 't mind , it 's time we milked the alpacas .
Milk the what ?
[ ALPACAS BLEATING SOFTLY ]
It 's not like milking a goat .
You don 't get a lot of milk from an alpaca .
It takes great patience and technique .
And , of course , you have to be very gentle with the , uh , boobs .
But once you get them warmed up ...
Oh . Nice one , dad .
Yeah , I find mixing a little fennel into their feed
increases the yield and improves the flavor .
- Would you like a taste ? - Oh , no .
Um , lactose intolerant .
Your loss .
Sweetie ?
[ DOWN-TEMPO ROCK MUSIC PLAYING THROUGH HEADPHONES ]
[ KNOCK ON DOOR ]
Can you open the door , please ?
I 'm so sorry .
I-I don 't ... I don 't know what came over me .
Lavinia , come on . Please open the door .
Uh , is there anyone else living on the property ,
aside from your family ?
There 's Ezra , our squatter , but he keeps to himself .
I haven 't seen him in months .
Would it be okay if I talk with him ?
You can try . I mean , Benny can show you the way .
Yeah . Yeah , for sure .
But I can 't promise he 's gonna talk to you .
He 's , um , special .
[ THUNDER RUMBLING ]
[ CHIMES TINKLING ]
WARD : Looks like there 's a storm coming in .
BENNY : Yeah .
Are those cameras ?
BENNY : Yeah . Ezra used to be an electrician back in the day .
He 's got this whole place wired up .
- Oh . - [
MID-TEMPO MUSIC PLAYING ]
Where 's his juice come from ?
Solar . Totally off the grid .
Hey ! Ezra !
You got a visitor !
Oh ! It 's the surveyor man !
I 'm sorry . I don 't think we 've met yet .
- I 'm , uh ... - The hydrologist .
Yeah .
Pretty well informed .
Lot of little birdies flitting around here in this ecosphere .
You just got to know how to decode them .
Come on in .
We 'll talk about the space metal .
- Want a hit ? - Oh , no , thank you .
I didn 't think so .
Hey , some java ?
- WARD : Yeah . - All right .
[ CAT MEOWS ]
Aw . What 's her name ?
- BENNY : G-spot . - What ?
BENNY : What ? Come on . That 's like the coolest name ever .
A pussy named G-spot ? It 's totally hilarious .
Hey . Come here , lady .
Hi .
All right .
Oh , yeah , you like this ? You like that ?
Hey , my apologies for the Adam 's ale .
- Here you go . - Thank you .
Yeah , the H2O has gone a little brackish .
Yeah , I can 't ... I can 't smell anything .
It 's probably just rust from the taps .
Have you tried running the faucet , see if it runs clear ?
Hey , that , my friend , is straight from the mother 's tit .
BENNY : Yeah , we 've had some problems with the well before
but only in the summer .
Something about the aquifer .
Right . Yeah .
That 's to do with the level of the water table , but ...
I don 't know . Shouldn 't be happening this time of year .
Freshest water in the department .
That 's what Dad always says .
I 'm sure it 's fine ,
but if you want I could run a test on a sample .
I have all my equipment back up in the tent .
So , you know , better safe than sorry .
Hey , knock yourself out .
[ THUNDER CRASHES ]
[ RAIN PATTERING ]
All right !
BENNY : Damn , that was close .
EZRA : Tell it , baby . Tell it , tell it !
It 's so beautiful .
[ THUNDER CRASHING ]
NATHAN : Lavinny , what are you doing ?
Come on . Let 's go back inside .
It 's drawing the lightning .
TOOMA : In my next term as your mayor ,
we will be undertaking the largest infrastructure project
in our city 's history with the construction
of the freshwater reservoir on the Miskatonic ...
[ CRACKLING ] The economic impact alone ...
[ STATIC CRACKLING ]
[ CELLPHONE RINGS ]
Hello ?
[ STATIC CRACKLING ]
Who is that ?
- [ RUSTLING ] - [ DIAL TONE ]
[ DIAL TONE STOPS ]
What the hell ?
[ ENGINE STARTS ]
[ ENGINE REVVING ]
- [ ENGINE STOPS ] - [ GASPS ]
[ BREATHING SHALLOWLY ]
[ CREAKING ]
How can something that big just disappear ?
I don 't know , but I 'm glad .
Did you plant those ?
THERESA : No . Maybe they 're perennials .
[ HORN HONKS ]
Great . Here comes the circus .
Baby .
[ INTRO THEME PLAYS ]
WOMAN : Could you please tell us exactly what happened ?
NATHAN : Well , there was a boom .
Uh , it was a couple nights ago .
A boom and a flash of light and a vibration ,
and we came out , and we saw this large rock .
Horrible . Hideous . Oh , my God .
Couldn 't somebody have given me a comb ? Jesus !
I 'm here with Arkham resident Nathan Gardner ,
who claims that an unidentified flying object
landed in his front yard last night .
" UFO witness " ?
You said UFO ! I didn 't say UFO !
Oh , for fuck 's sake .
Theresa , can you get out here , please ?
JACK : Did you see a UFO ? I didn 't see any UFO .
WOMAN : Right , and , uh ...
We had a top hydrologist here ...
not a geologist ...
Yeah , I think the freaked-out-abductee look
suits you pretty well .
WOMAN : Very good .
So the meteorite ,
which happened to mysteriously disappear
before the time my team and I got here .
How does an object of that size ...
Theresa , can you please get out here ?
Mr. Gardner , were you sober
at the time that this event happened ?
Uh , well , I mean , I like a bit of bourbon .
Um , uh , it comes out of Texas .
Oh , for fuck 's sake .
I was ... I was not ... The night before ,
I had a few drinks , but I wasn 't ...
I was sober when I came out .
- BENNY : Oh , man . - Jack , go get your mother .
Okay .
What part of " meteorite " do you not understand ?
[ INDISTINCT TALKING ]
Mom .
I wouldn 't classify that as mental illness .
MAN : WARK News .
Daddy ! Mommy 's hurt !
Baby ?
Dinner 's ready .
WOMAN : ... calling the family 's claim into question .
THERESA : God , why did I do that ?
NATHAN : It 's all right .
THERESA : [ GROANS ]
- Keep your hand elevated . - Okay .
- NATHAN : Just keep it up . - Yeah .
We 'll call you from the hospital .
Benny , you 're man of the house .
And I want those alpacas back in the barn by 10 : 00 .
- BENNY : You got it , Dad . - 10 : 00 !
[ CAR DOOR OPENS ]
[ CAR DOOR CLOSES ]
[ ENGINE STARTS ]
What are we gonna do ?
I don 't know . You 're the man of the house .
Come on , Jack-Jack . Time for bed .
Benny will look after us because he 's so responsible .
Race you upstairs .
Come on . Come on .
Come on .
LAVINIA : Benny ?
Benny , get your stupid ass out here now !
Fuck . What ?
You were supposed to feed the alpacas .
I already did .
What are you talking about ? They 're standing right there .
BENNY : I already fed them .
- LAVINIA : Well ... - What the ... ?
Get them into the barn , okay ?
And lay off the weed , all right ?
I can 't fucking do this on my own , okay ?
- Go . - Okay .
Go ! Just do it already !
Harpy . Harridan . Hairy ax wound .
Maggot dick .
Jeez .
Hey , girl .
JACK : [ WHISTLING ]
Come on , girl .
[ WHISTLES ]
Jack ?
[ WHISTLING ]
What are you doing ?
Shh !
[ WHISPERING ] It 's talking to me .
Who ? Who 's talking to you ?
The man in the well .
[ WHISTLING ]
LAVINIA : Okay .
- [ WHISTLING ] - [ STOMACH RUMBLES ]
[ TENSE MUSIC PLAYS ]
[ WHISTLE ]
[ CELLPHONE RINGS ]
Dad ? Hello ?
[ GARBLED VOICE ]
Dad ?
Hello ?
[ GARBLED VOICE SCREAMING ]
Hello ? Lavinia ?
Is that you ?
[ GARBLED VOICE ]
[ WHISTLE ]
[ CHITTERING ]
[ SHRIEKS ]
WOMAN : A weather report for Arkham County ,
Innsmouth , Aylesbury , Dunwich , Kingsport ...
Low temperature around 54 degrees .
- High near ... - [ STATIC
CRACKLING ]
- [ FAUCET TURNS ON ] - [
SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY ]
Don 't puke . Don 't puke .
[ CLOCK TICKING ]
[ TICKING SLOWS , STOPS ]
[ KNIFE CLATTERS ]
[ CELLPHONE RINGS ]
Dad ?
[ GARBLED VOICES ]
[ STOMACH RUMBLES ]
[ RETCHING ]
[ COUGHING ]
[ KNOCK ON DOOR ]
Lavinia , hey .
Um , this really isn 't a good time .
Are you guys okay ?
Um , no , I 'm not feeling too well .
All right , well ,
that 's actually what I want to talk to you about .
I think there 's something wrong with the water here ,
some kind of contamination .
Sorry , what ?
A contamination with the ... the water .
- Um , I don 't know exactly what . - [ STOMACH RUMBLES ]
But , um , we 're sending a sample back to the lab in Arkham .
- [ GULPS ] - In the meantime ...
I believe it , science guy .
Hey , try not to drink the water , okay ?
[ SIGHS ]
Hey , kiddo . What are you up to ?
Playing with my friends .
Okeydokey . Well , um , have fun , okay ?
- [ WHISTLE ] - [ LAUGHING ]
[ CHIMES TINKLING ]
Ezra ?
Hey , make yourself comfortable , amigo .
What the hell are you doing down there ?
I 'm reorganizing .
- Oh , want some java ? - Uh , no , thank you .
That 's actually what I wanted to talk to you about .
I don 't think you should be drinking that .
I found something in the water . Just a trace , really .
Um ... Hey , where 's G-spot ?
Heh ! Who knows ?
Caterwauling out there somewhere .
Really haven 't seen her since it all started .
Since what all started ?
Shh !
You can hear them down there .
H-Hear them ? Hear who ?
[ STATIC CRACKLING , RINGING ]
Yeah , I could hear them while I slept ,
shuffling around , chattering .
See , I knew no one would believe me unless I got it on Memorex .
What exactly am I supposed to be listening to ?
The people under the floor , dude .
The aliens .
They 're there .
Well , yeah , it is strange .
But it 's probably geothermal activity
- or magnetic distortions . - No , no .
Something like that .
They came on the rock .
Look , no offense , Ezra , but that 's pretty out there .
[ CHUCKLES ] You don 't get it , do you ?
It 's not out there . It 's in here .
It 's in the static . It 's in the moisture .
Up is down . Fast is slow .
What 's in here is out there ,
and what 's out there is in here now .
Comprendo ?
Um , look ,
why don 't you think about getting out of here for a while ?
I 'm gonna be back tomorrow .
I 'll have some more equipment with me .
I 'm sure it will all make more sense in the morning .
Morning ?
Dude , it 's already morning .
All right . Um , stick to bottled water , okay ?
Oh , hey , I will let you know if I see G-spot .
You might see her , but I don 't think you 'll recognize her .
[ SINGING OPERATICALLY ]
Nathan .
Doing okay ? We 're almost there .
Yeah . I just feel so stupid .
I mean , I just don 't even know what I was thinking .
And I don 't even want to think about
how many clients I pissed off by not getting back to them .
- Mm . - The surgery was successful .
That 's the important thing .
Look out ! Aah !
[ TIRES SCREECH ]
[ CAT YOWLS ]
[ GASPS ]
- Christ , that was close . - What ... What ...
Did you see that thing ? What was that thing ?
- Did you see its eyes ? - Oh , my God .
What are you doing ?
I-I want to call the kids , just check that they 're okay .
Honey , the kids are fine .
[ RINGING ]
[ DOG SNIFFING ]
[ WHISTLE ]
[ GROWLING ]
[ BARKING ]
[ DOG BARKING ]
[ WHISTLING ]
[ STATIC CRACKLING ]
[ BUZZING ]
[ BUZZING STOPS ]
What are you doing in my room ?
- Where have you been ? - I was out in the back field .
I thought I heard Sam . I was worried about him .
Look , I know it sounds weird ,
but I kind of got lost out there .
You know , like , one second it was daytime ,
then all of a sudden it was so dark
I couldn 't even find the house .
[ CELLPHONE RINGING ]
What the hell is going on ?
It 's probably Dad .
At least I hope it 's Dad .
[ RINGING CONTINUES ]
Dad ?
[ GARBLED VOICES ]
[ BEEPS ]
Who was that ?
I 'm not sure .
[ CELLPHONE RINGS ]
Christ , now what ?
Wait , where 's Jack ?
[ TENSE MUSIC PLAYING ]
Baby , what are you doing out here all by yourself ?
JACK : Mommy !
- NATHAN : Jack . - Jack !
Oh , my God .
What is wrong with you two ?
Why is your brother out here by himself ?
- No , it didn 't happen that way . - NATHAN : What is this ?
While the cat 's away , the mice will play ?
Isn 't that right ?
I 'm seriously disappointed in both of you .
No , there was this sound , and I got sick ,
and then you called and yelled at me .
Honey , what are you talking about ?
We couldn 't even get through , and believe me , we tried .
She 's telling the truth , Dad . Something weird is going on .
I don 't want to hear your excuses either , Benny .
I 'm gonna take him upstairs .
I 'll leave you to deal with these two .
BENNY : Holy shit .
NATHAN : Holy shit .
They should have been put back in the barn hours ago .
You haven 't even fed them yet , have you ?
- Dad , I tried , but ... - What do you mean , you tried ?
Do you have any idea how much those animals cost us ?
They are alpacas !
Alpacas .
Dad ...
I mean , should we , like , try to warn him .
LAVINIA : Warn him about what ?
Sam ?
Come on . Come on .
Sam ? Here , boy .
Stupid goddamn dog .
You too , huh ?
You know , if I could just get
a little consideration around here ,
just a little support ,
it would be greatly fucking appreciated .
LAVINIA : Dad 's acting weird , right ?
BENNY : You noticed ?
Where 's Sam ?
T-They must have got him .
They ?
Uh , what the fuck are you talking about ?
They , them , it .
That thing that has been fucking this place up .
I mean , come on , Dad .
Don 't pretend that you haven 't noticed .
Nothing has been fucking this place up .
Why are you so in denial ?
Okay , you know , I 've had it with your drama , Lavinia ,
so do me a favor and get the fuck out of my sight , okay ?
No , no , actually , I 'll save you the trouble
and get the fuck out of yours !
Look , he doesn 't mean it .
Do you still have that girlfriend in Aylesbury ?
Well , she wasn 't my girlfriend ,
and I haven 't seen her in months .
Why ?
Because we need to get the hell out of here .
JACK : Look .
THERESA : Make him really scary .
Oh , yes .
What ?
Uh , are you okay ?
No , I just blew up at Lavinia .
I don 't think I 'll be winning any " father of the year " awards .
Oh , she 's that age . She 's just impossible .
[ CREAKING ]
Aah !
- Aah ! - [ STOMPING ]
[ GROANING ]
Aah !
THERESA : No , baby . No more .
We need to call a plumber or an exterminator .
Drains got shit growing in them .
So many crumbs on the bed .
Do you think Sam is with Grandpa ?
No , baby , Grandpa is in heaven , and Sam just ,
I don 't know , he found a friend or went for a walk .
But he was scared . He was growling .
I could see all of his teeth like this .
[ IMITATING GROWLING ]
- Don 't do that face . - Oh , God . What is that smell ?
What smell ? We washed everything .
What is it , like ... like damp or drains ?
No , I-I 've been smelling it
ever since the night that thing hit the farm .
Maybe it 's , like , the black mold in the basement coming up .
It 's exactly the same smell
as the cancer ward where my father was .
You know , death , disinfectant .
The cancer smell . Rotting milk . You know the smell .
You know the cancer smell better than anybody .
And now the dog has vanished off the face of the Earth ,
so connect those dots .
I told you Sam was with Grandpa !
No , he 's not . Oh , my God , I just ...
Ugh ! Stop saying that !
No , no , no , Jack , Jack , Sam is fine .
JACK : Is he really ?
Honey , would you please take it easy ?
It 's a miracle the hospital even let you go home .
I just have to get online . All right ?
I have so much work I have to do .
- Daddy ? - Yeah , I 'll take care of ...
Everything 's gonna be A-OK .
MAN : Be careful not to overwater all the plants .
Mount the spray to remind you ... it 's easy to forget ...
so try setting a timer to make sure overwatering never occurs .
Even , steady watering is every master gardener 's secret
and the key to harvesting
those plump , juicy , flavorful tomatoes
that last throughout the season .
Just look at you beauties . And a month early .
... makes for a perfect arrangement .
[ SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ]
Peaches !
Heh .
Hoo hoo hoo hoo hoo !
You do that very well , Theresa Peach .
If we went to 143-9 and kept it under the 10 handle ,
that could actually ...
What ? Not dollars .
Euros ? Christ , uh , um ...
Then there should be at least a two-pip spread .
What ? What ?
Can you hear me ?
Hello ?
[ STATIC CRACKLING ]
Fuck !
You have got to do something about that dish .
I am literally hemorrhaging clients .
It should be working , sweetie . I just checked it this morning .
No , it 's garbling the fuck out of everything I say .
[ SPITS ]
Nate ?
[ SPITTING ]
Nate , are you listening to me ?
You know , I did everything I was supposed to do !
I followed every fucking rule in the book ,
and they still fucking taste like shit , so you know what ? !
Fuck that .
Okay ! Coming up !
Okay , stop it ! Stop .
Slam dunk !
You know what ? ! Just do something about that dish .
All right . Do you know what ?
I 'm gonna go and lie down .
- [ GRUNTS ] - [ TRASH CAN THUDS ]
But just fix that dish , okay ? !
[ GARGLES , SPITS ]
[ COUGHS ] Yeah , I think it 's a good idea , sweetie .
[ CORK SQUEAKS ]
I should have grown barley .
Ain 't that right , Dad ?
TOOMA : That is why , in my next term as your mayor ,
we will be undertaking the largest infrastructure project
in our city 's history with the construction
of a freshwater reservoir on the Miska ...
MAN : Well , Katie , you also have people
with different views on this .
You have scientists who very much dispute it .
So is there climate change ?
Will it go back ? Will it change back ?
Probably . I believe so .
Mankind ... I mean men and women ...
[ TENSE MUSIC PLAYING ]
[ BUZZING ]
Dad ?
- Whoa . - Mm .
Pretty beautiful , huh , buddy ?
Help me .
Protect me .
Get me out of here .
[ GROANS ]
Jack ?
[ ALPACAS GROWLING SOFTLY ]
[ TENSE MUSIC PLAYING ]
What 's happening to them ?
Uh , I-I don 't know .
Go . Go . Go !
- Go ! - THERESA : Oh , my God !
Mom !
NATHAN : Benny ?
Benny .
[ MUFFLED MOANING ]
Oh , my God .
[ MOANING CONTINUES ]
- Oh , my God . - Oh , my God .
Oh , my God .
Let 's ...
[ GASPING ]
... take them in the house .
Benny , call 911 . Call an ambulance .
Okay .
Come on , hurry up . Get the operator .
THERESA : [ GASPING AND WHIMPERING ]
It 's not working . I can 't get a dial tone .
What do you mean , you can 't get a dial tone ?
Just give it to me .
All this static .
- Fuck ! - BENNY : There 's nothing there .
- I can 't get a dial tone . - How hard can it be to dial 911 ?
BENNY : Yeah , I told you . There 's no one there !
- What are we gonna do ? - What are these sounds ?
- Fuck ! - [ CELLPHONE CLATTERS ]
- Lavinny . - Vinny .
NATHAN : Lavinia , what did you do to yourself ?
Lavinny .
[ SCREAMS ]
[ ENGINE CRANKING ]
[ CRANKING CONTINUES ]
You cocksucker . You fucking cocksucker !
You cocksucker ! You cocksucker !
Aah ! Aah ! Aah ! Aah ! Aah ! Aah !
Aah ! Aah ! Aah ! Aah ! Aah ! Aah ! Aah !
Aah ! Aah ! Aah ! Aah ! Aah !
Aah ! Aah ! Aah !
[ PANTING ]
- [ WHIMPERING AND MOANING ] - Looks like she 's absorbing him .
Trying to reassimilate him into her body .
Don 't say that .
Shh , it 's okay .
[ SQUELCHING ]
I 'm here , Mom .
- I 'm right here . - [ MOANING CONTINUES ]
I mean , how can any of this even be possible ?
That thing from the meteorite happened to them .
It changes everything around it .
Not just matter .
Time as well .
Time , it stretches around it ,
like when you 're approaching a black hole , right ?
I mean ... I mean , how long have we been sitting here ?
How long has it been since Dad went out to the car ?
God , I think she 's trying to talk to us .
[ EXHALES SHARPLY ]
What was that , Mom ?
[ CROAKS ]
No , this is useless .
- We 've got to get help . - No , wait .
We 're gonna die in this fucking place .
The , uh ,
car is not happening .
What do you mean , the car is not happening ?
What does that mean ?
Something sucked the charge out of the battery overnight .
Probably the same thing
that 's screwing with the cells and the computers .
It 's like an electromagnetic field .
And you believe me now ?
I don 't know what I believe anymore .
[ GAGGING ]
[ WHIMPERING AND MOANING ]
Why do they keep making that sound ? !
[ MOANING ]
I don 't think they like the sunlight , Dad .
- I think it 's hurting them . - We 've got to do something .
Help me get them up the stairs .
Easy does it .
You got her ? You got her ?
BENNY : Yeah .
Lavinia , put the mattress down .
[ WHIMPERING AND MOANING CONTINUES ]
LAVINIA : Mom .
JACK : [ CRYING ]
[ CRYING , SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ]
Uh , we 're here , Mom .
It 's gonna be okay .
JACK : [ WEAKLY ] Daddy ...
[ CRYING ]
You want me to get you some water ?
[ GRUNTING ]
[ CRYING ]
[ ALPACAS SCREECHING ]
Something 's happening to the alpacas .
You two stay here with Jack and your mother .
Everything 's under control .
Dad ?
You son of a bitch .
You 're gonna leave my family alone now .
You 're gonna leave my family alone .
Haven 't we been through enough ?
Haven 't we ?
[ ALPACAS GROWLING AND SCREECHING ]
Aah !
[ SCREECHING ]
Aaah !
Aaaah !
[ GRUNTS ]
- Aah ! - [ GUNSHOT ]
Aah ! Aaaah !
[ SOBS ]
[ SOBBING ]
Shooting stopped .
I hope he 's okay .
Him ?
And are we okay ? Is any of this okay ?
[ WHIMPERING ]
BENNY : [ VOICE BREAKING ] I can 't take this .
Make it stop .
We 've got to get off this farm .
Tonight .
BENNY : Dad .
Go downstairs , both of you .
[ SOFT MOANING ]
- But ... - Just do as I say , please .
What are you gonna do ?
Handle it .
Like you handled the alpacas ?
Get out .
[ CRYING ] Come on .
You 've done all you could .
[ CRYING ] I 'm sorry , Mom .
Sorry , Jack .
- BENNY : Love you , Dad . - I love you too .
Theresa baby ,
I 'm really trying to do my best .
Shh .
[ BREATHING SHALLOWLY ]
[ WHIMPERING ]
You will always be my golden lady .
Now , you want to know what I 'm gonna do ?
I 'm gonna go outside , and I 'm gonna find you some help .
I promise .
And then we 're gonna take that trip we 've been talking about .
Okay , baby ?
Oh , yeah .
That 's what we 're gonna do .
Holy shit , that 's what we 're gonna do .
TOOMA : I don 't care about someone identifying
fucking contamination in the groundwater !
The contracts have already been signed .
- Do you think those ... - If you 'll follow me .
Would you like a glass of water ?
WARD : No , thank you .
That 's actually why I 'm here .
TOOMA : ... half the drinking water for the East Coast !
PIERCE : Ward !
Can you come here for a sec ?
You know Jake .
Tell him .
Found these by the Gardner place .
Oh , my God .
What happened to them ? They look burned .
PIERCE : I don 't know .
Jake said he found them bunched up
like they were running from something .
Got a couple birds in there , a white-tail , rabbit .
Got a fucking cat .
It looks like radiation burns .
LAVINIA : [ WHISPERING ] Shut up !
What 's your problem ? Come on .
Go get the tack .
Well , I , uh ...
It 's real dark back there , so ...
And ?
I 'll just go get the tack , then .
Benny , just be careful .
I don 't want to lose you too .
Come on . Shh , shh , shh .
Leech . Nightmare . Leprous spellcaster .
Asshat .
- [ HORSE NEIGHING ] - Comet .
Don 't look .
Whoa ! Steady , boy . Steady .
[ NEIGHING ]
Comet , steady . Be steady .
Steady .
Jesus , Benny , you nearly gave me a heart attack .
Com , steady . Come on .
- Comet ... - What 's wrong with the horse ?
There 's nothing wrong with the horse .
Right now Comet is the last thing you need to be afraid of .
Fuck ! No , Comet .
Fuck .
Looks like we 're gonna have to walk out of here .
In the dark ?
Through 12 miles of ancient woodland ?
[ EXHALES SHARPLY ]
[ HOWL ECHOES ]
Sam ?
LAVINIA : What are you doing ? We have to get out of here .
- Sam , is that you ? - [ YELP ECHOES ]
Benny . Benny !
Fuck !
He sounds hurt .
[ WHIMPER ECHOES ]
Hold on , boy !
- What are you doing ? - We can 't just leave him .
Are you out of your fucking mind ?
I have to , all right ?
I 'll put him in the bucket , and then you can pull him up .
No , Benny ...
- Whoa ! Whoa . - Fuck this .
No , give me your hand . It is just a dog .
- Please give me your hand . - It 's gonna take two minutes .
- Come back up , please . - It 's gonna take two minutes .
Idiot .
Benny !
God , jeez .
Smells like something died down here .
[ COUGHING ]
[ GRUNTING ]
Sam ?
- [ YELP ECHOES ] - LAVINIA : Come on !
BENNY : I-I can see him moving .
LAVINIA : What is it ? What do you see ?
[ RUMBLING ]
No ! No , no , no !
No !
[ SCREAMING ]
[ SCREAMS ]
Benny !
- No ! - [ SCREAMING FADES ]
[ SOBBING ] No .
Aah !
I have been looking all over for you !
You expect me to do everything on my own , huh ?
The both of you .
I mean , whatever happened
to the good old-fashioned concept of teamwork ? !
If we could all just pull together
just once for the sake of your mother .
[ CRYING ] Daddy ! You 're hurting me !
Honey . Honey , I 'm not that .
No , I 'm not a monster .
I know I 'm not my dad . I know .
Please don 't make me go in there .
I promise . I 'll do whatever you want .
I 'll ... I 'll ... I 'll clean up my language .
I 'll even clean up my room .
Well , it 's like I said , Lavinia .
- We 're a family . - No .
Now , if there 's one thing that families do , they stay together .
- Now feed your mother . - [ SOBS ]
Dad !
[ CRYING ]
Please !
But , Dad !
You seeing this ?
Wait , is that Lavinia 's horse ?
[ HORSE NEIGHS ]
[ SIREN WAILING ]
I put your favorite movie on .
I know this one by heart .
You have a little something in your eyes , you know ?
Oh .
I think after Roman Colosseum
we should go Corsica ,
Malta , Greek Isles .
Greek Isles are the best .
[ WAILING ] Dad !
Please !
[ SCREAMING ]
[ SOBBING ]
THERESA : [ GROWLING ] Lavinia !
- Lavinia ! - [ SCREAMING ]
Lavinia !
[ TENSE MUSIC PLAYS ]
You never know .
Mr. Gardner ?
- Lavinia ? - [ BANGING ]
- Oh , shit . - What ?
It 's you . Toxologist .
I 'm the hydrologist , sir , yeah .
Um , we came to make sure you 're okay .
NATHAN : That 's very kind of you .
We 've been having a hard time , you know ?
The car and telephone and Wi-Fi .
Heh . Life in the sticks .
Come in .
Theresa will be happy to see you .
I 'm hungry !
[ GROWLS ]
I 'm hungry .
Mom . Mom .
- Mommy ! - I 'm hungry .
What happened to your arms ?
It 's just a rash .
Where 's your wife ?
She 's right there .
And the rest of your family ?
Everybody 's here . We all stick together .
What ?
Theresa says , " Except for Benny .
Benny lives in the well now . "
LAVINIA : [ SCREAMING ]
Drink ? I 'm having one .
- [ GROWLING ] Lavinia ! - Mom !
Lavinia !
Mom , stop !
Ward !
Out of the way .
LAVINIA : [ SCREAMING ]
- No ! - [ GROWLING ]
Please , Mommy !
No , no !
[ MOANING ]
- [ SCREECHES ] - [ GUNSHOT ]
[ GASPING ]
[ WEAKLY ] Daddy ...
- [ GUNSHOT ] - LAVINIA : [ GASPS ]
They 're not my family .
[ PANTING ]
LAVINIA : [ CRYING ] Daddy ...
[ COUGHING ]
WARD : Lavinia . Lavinia ! Lavinia .
Come here .
All right . It 's gonna be okay , all right ?
You 're gonna be okay . I mean ...
Fuck ! I 'm gonna carry you .
I 'm gonna carry you outside in the patrol car , okay ?
I got you . Oh , God .
You 're okay .
Okay , we 're almost there .
The color .
Ward !
- No ! - [ GUNSHOT ]
[ SCREAMING ] Dad !
[ CRYING ] Fuck ! You shot my dad ! Look !
Look what you did !
Dad .
[ PANTING ]
Beautiful .
Like a flower .
It 's gonna be okay , Dad , now .
You can help us .
Three Charlie one seven . I 've got a code 33 .
D-Don 't ...
Don 't ...
Please don 't leave me .
Daddy ?
I 'm not getting anything . We 've got to get out of here .
We 're not getting out of here .
None of us are .
That thing won 't let us .
Come on , look , that ... that 's silly .
There 's nothing stopping us from getting up and leav ...
[ RUMBLING ]
What the hell was that ?
It sounded like it came from Ezra 's cabin .
We can 't leave him out there on his own .
Ward , give me a hand .
Lavinia .
I 'm not going with you .
We 've got to go .
I 'm sorry , we 've got to go . You ... You can 't stay here .
I live here .
I 'm gonna come back for you .
I 'll be back .
EZRA : [ DEEP VOICE ] Nothing .
Nothing . Nothing .
Nothing .
- Ezra ? - Cold and wet .
You in there ?
But it burns .
I 'm going in .
Sucking the life out of everything .
It came down in the rock .
Ezra ?
[ VOICE DISTORTING ] It lives in the well .
It grew down there .
WARD : Ezra ?
Poisoning everything .
Changing everything
into something like the world it came from .
Into what it knows .
We all know it 's coming , but we can 't get away .
It 's got everything that lives .
They all drunk the water .
It got strong .
Sheriff .
Fed itself on them .
It came from the stars ...
Skin 's all
where things ain 't like they are here .
It 's just a color .
But it burns .
It sucks , and it burns .
Sheriff ! No ! Sheriff !
It burns .
[ GUNSHOT ]
Sheriff ?
[ SOFT GROWLING ]
[ MOANS ]
[ PANTING ]
Lavinia ?
It 's so beautiful .
[ TENSE MUSIC PLAYS ]
[ MOANING ]
Lavinia !
LAVINIA : No , Jack !
BENNY : It 's you , Jack .
JACK : Now it 's Lavinia .
THERESA : There 's something wrong with Jack !
Why does it matter how far away it is ? Look at him .
LAVINIA 'S VOICE : Are you looking at my legs ?
You 're dead , Nathan !
It 's no big deal .
[ INDISTINCT TALKING ]
Don 't make ... Stay away .
JACK : Daddy !
No ! No !
[ GROANING ]
[ MUSIC INTENSIFIES ]
[ MUSIC FADES ]
[ DOWN-TEMPO MUSIC PLAYS ]
WARD : I hope the dammed water that covers this place
will be very deep .
But even then
I will never drink it .
There are only a few of us that remember the strange days now .
What touched this place cannot be quantified
or understood by human science .
It was just a color out of space
a messenger from realms whose existence stuns the brain
and numbs us with the gulfs
that it throws open before our frenzied eyes .